[
  {
    "subject": "SocialStudies",
    "disabled": "no",
    "topics": [
      {
        "topic": "KnowingOurEarth",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "What is a Globe ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["a flat surface", "a toy", "a model of earth"],
                "correct": "a model of earth"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "We can hang ____ on the wall.",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["globe", "atlas", "wall maps"],
                "correct": "wall maps"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "What is a map ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["a model of earth", "a drawing of the earth", "a map that we can hang on wall"],
                "correct": "a drawing of the earth"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "What is an atlas ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["a model of earth", "a book of maps", "a drawing of the earth", "a map that we can hang on wall"],
                "correct": "a book of maps"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Moon and other planet get light from ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["sun", "earth", "fire", "mars"],
                "correct": "sun"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "The ____ colour on the map of the world, shows water.",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["red", "blue", "green"],
                "correct": "blue"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Very large water bodies are called ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["sea", "pond", "ocean"],
                "correct": "ocean"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "The ____ is the largest ocean in the world.",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["pacific ocean", "atlantic ocean", "arctic ocean"],
                "correct": "pacific ocean"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "The ____ is the smallest ocean in the world.",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["pacific ocean", "atlantic ocean", "arctic ocean"],
                "correct": "arctic ocean"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "A ____ helps us to find directions.",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["globe", "compass", "map"],
                "correct": "compass"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Needle of the compass always point to ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["east", "west", "north", "south"],
                "correct": "north"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Why do we use compass ____ ",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["to find directions", "to find ocean and continents", "to find water bodies"],
                "correct": "to find directions"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Book of map is called ____ ",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["atlas", "a map book", "a drawing book", "a book"],
                "correct": "atlas"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "What does the blue colour of the map shows ____ ",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["oceans", "seas", "river and lakes", "all of these"],
                "correct": "all of these"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Large land masses are called ____ ",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["continents", "countries", "cities", "oceans"],
                "correct": "continents"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "A globe is rotated to see the other half of the world ____ ",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["true", "false"],
                "correct": "true"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "A globe is a drawing of earth or a part of it ____ ",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["true", "false"],
                "correct": "false"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "A very large body of water is called continent ____ ",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["true", "false"],
                "correct": "false"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "A compass helps us to find maps ____ ",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["true", "false"],
                "correct": "false"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "The blue colour on the map shows water ____ ",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["true", "false"],
                "correct": "true"
            }
          }
        ]
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "subject": "Maths",
    "disabled": "no",
    "topics": [
      {
        "topic": "PredecessorSuccessor",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "Predecessor of 6345 is ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["6346", "6344", "6245", "5345"],
                "correct": "6344"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Predecessor of 2532 is ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["2531", "2432", "1532", "2533"],
                "correct": "2531"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Predecessor of 4000 is ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["3999", "4001", "2638", "3000"],
                "correct": "3999"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Successor of 7999 is ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["8999", "8000", "7883", "1222"],
                "correct": "8000"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Successor of 8173 is ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["9173", "8174", "8172", "8273"],
                "correct": "8174"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Successor of 2450 is ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["3450", "2550", "2451", "2452"],
                "correct": "2451"
            }
          }
        ]
      },
	  {
	    "topic": "CompareNumbers",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "735 ____ 1488",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["<",">","="],
                "correct": "<"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "9178 ____ 178",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["<",">","="],
                "correct": ">"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "4213 ____ 5075",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["<",">","="],
                "correct": "<"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "3442 ____ 3442",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["<",">","="],
                "correct": "="
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "7015 ____ 7638",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["<",">","="],
                "correct": "<"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "999 ____ 4175",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["<",">","="],
                "correct": "<"
            }
          }
        ]
      },
      {
  	    "topic": "GreatestSmallestNumberDigits",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "Greatest number with 3,8,0",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["308","380","803", "830"],
                "correct": "830"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Greatest number with 3,5,1",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["351","135","531", "513"],
                "correct": "531"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Greatest number with 5,0,9,3",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["5093","5930","9530", "3950"],
                "correct": "9530"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Smallest number with 3,8,0",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["308","380","803", "830"],
                "correct": "308"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Smallest number with 3,5,1",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["351","135","531", "513"],
                "correct": "135"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Smallest number with 5,0,9,3",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["5093","5930","9530", "3950"],
                "correct": "3059"
            }
          }
        ]
      },
      {
  	    "topic": "RoundingOff",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "Round off to nearest tens: 73",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["70","60","80", "30"],
                "correct": "70"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Round off to nearest tens: 235",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["240","230","260", "100"],
                "correct": "240"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Round off to nearest tens: 627",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["620","630","600", "670"],
                "correct": "630"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Round off to nearest tens: 194",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["190","200","170", "100"],
                "correct": "190"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Round off to nearest tens: 943",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["940","950","1000", "850"],
                "correct": "940"
            }
          }
        ]
      },
      {
  	    "topic": "SkipCounting",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "Skip count in 10: 3590",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["3600","3490","4590"],
                "correct": "3600"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Skip count in 10: 3620",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["3630","3730","4620"],
                "correct": "3630"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Skip count in 10: 9260",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["9270","9360","8260"],
                "correct": "9270"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Skip count in 10: 8575",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
                "options": ["8585","8595","7595"],
                "correct": "8585"
            }
          }
        ]
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "subject": "Science",
    "topics": [
      {
        "topic": "SafetyRules",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "Cross the road when pedestrian traffic light is ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["red", "green", "yellow"],
              "correct": "green"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "In the bus we must keep ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["dancing", "disturbing the driver", "quiet"],
              "correct": "quiet"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "We should not play ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["rough games", "indoor games", "cricket"],
              "correct": "rough games"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Safety rules to be followed ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["everywhere", "only in school", "only in bus"],
              "correct": "everywhere"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Do not play with ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["toys", "ball", "matchsticks"],
              "correct": "matchsticks"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "We should walk on the ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["road", "footpath", "road divider"],
              "correct": "footpath"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "We should sharpen our pencil with a ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["knife", "blade", "sharpner"],
              "correct": "sharpner"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "We should always use ____ to cross the road.",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["subway", "overbridge", "any of these"],
              "correct": "any of these"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "What can harm you ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["hot iron", "bed", "tree"],
              "correct": "hot iron"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "What can harm you ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["toy", "friend", "electric socket"],
              "correct": "electric socket"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "What can harm you ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["pencil", "gas stove", "book"],
              "correct": "gas stove"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "We must cross the road on ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["zebra crossing", "footpath"],
              "correct": "zebra crossing"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "We should not run on the ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["stairs", "playground"],
              "correct": "stairs"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "We must not ____ anybody for fun.",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["push", "help"],
              "correct": "push"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "When we get small wound, we should flush with ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["water", "antiseptic lotion"],
              "correct": "water"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "We should not play on the road ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["true", "false"],
              "correct": "true"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "It is dangerous to play with fire ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["true", "false"],
              "correct": "true"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "We may get injured in the playground, because of a  ____ game.",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["rough", "correct", "old"],
              "correct": "rough"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "First aid box must contain ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["tofees", "juice", "antiseptic lotion"],
              "correct": "antiseptic lotion"
            }
          }
        ]
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "subject": "EnglishLiterature",
    "topics": [
      {
        "topic": "AJourney",
        "questions": [
          {
            "question": "A ____ is a treasure trove of wisdom.",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["book", "caterpillar", "song"],
              "correct": "book"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "The ____ peeped from behind the trees.",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["moon", "sun", "stars"],
              "correct": "sun"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Clouds cool down and bring ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["apples", "rain", "flowers"],
              "correct": "rain"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "What did a child float in the river ____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["fish", "book", "paper boat"],
              "correct": "paper boat"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "A ____ is used for ferrying people.",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["boat", "both", "paper boat"],
              "correct": "boat"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Who troubled caterpillar's mother _____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["children", "snakes", "earthworms"],
              "correct": "children"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Caterpillar clung to the Page as it feared the _____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["dogs", "nasty birds", "cats"],
              "correct": "nasty birds"
            }
          },
          {
            "question": "Caterpillar began to weave strands of thread around it and _____",
            "type": "choice",
            "answer": {
              "options": ["slept", "danced", "cried"],
              "correct": "slept"
            }
          }
        ]
      }
    ]
  }
]
